Hello everyone.
Today we are going to solve the question of textbook of Class Lament which is Computer
Science with Python and we are going to solve the question of chapter 7 which is Python
fundamentals on page number 202.
So the question is write a program that displays a joke but display the punchline only when
the user presses Enter key.
So first we need to display a joke and then when user press the Enter key then we need
to display the punchline on the output.
So here I also gave an that is you may use input function.
So obviously without any function we are not able to ask the user to press Enter key.
So let's come to our VS code.
Here I already have created a file.
So let's do the code.
So first we need to display the joke.
So let's take a variable, joke and let's write the joke in this variable and let's store
the joke in this variable.
So the joke is I tried starting a hot air balloon business but it now took off.
So let's write it.
So it is a joke.
So this is a joke.
Now we need to store the punchline of that joke in a variable.
So let's create a variable of punchline with an punchline and let's write the punchline
store the punchline this variable.
So the punchline in this joke is that it never took off.
So let's write it.
All right.
Now in the output first we need to display the joke.
So to display anything we use a print function.
So here it is a print joke.
So we write joke.
Now here it is.
And now we will ask the user to press enter key.
So let's create a variable of name user and here we will ask from user with the help
of an interfunction input.
You can write it in text.
So we will write press enter key.
And when user will press enter key the output the punchline should be printed.
So let's print the punchline here.
All right.
Let's run this code.
So here is the joke.
I tried to study the hardware value business but it never took off.
So to display the punchline we need to press enter key.
So we press enter and here it is written punchline which is it now took off.
So that's it for today.
Thank you.