So, hey guys, welcome back to
my channel and today we will
solve another question of chapter 9
flow of control of class 11
and the subject is computer science
with Python. The page number is
332. We are solving type C
programming practice slash
knowledge based questions and today
we will solve question number 7.
Let's read question number 7.
write a short program to input
our digit and print it in
words
so we have to input single
digit one by one
and then we have to convert
it into words
we will ask the user if
the value is 0 then print
it as 0
if it is 1 then print
it as 1
So, this is how we can
watch print the digits, right?
So, let's open this code and
I have already created a file.
So, let's take input from the
user.
So, n is equal to int
input enter digit.
Now, we will ask here if
that digit is equal to 0.
So, what should we do?
Print 0.
and if that digit is, we
will use elif for that, we
can't use it again and again
so to ask again and again,
we use elif
so elif n is equal to
if that value is 1, then
you print that it is 1
now we will copy it because
we are going to use it
a lot
We will copy it and paste
it here.
If it is 2, then write
2.
You can increase the speed of
the video if you want.
Because it will take time.
We will keep copying till 9.
So, we know that we cannot
do that.
5, elif , n is equal to
2.
I copied and pasted it.
I didn't paste it.
I am writing it straight.
6, paste and then 7.
9 last
and now we will write one
more condition
condition means
else condition
if there is nothing from these
then what is it
you have put invalid value
nothing is there
in that value let's write zero
have any other have nine heaven
If it is 3.4, then it
will convert it to float, but
it will not convert it to
float because it is an integer.
I mean, why will it convert
it to float? Sorry, I said
it last time.
I put the value in float,
so it should have been converted
to integer.
Okay, there is an integer written
here, so it will also take
the integer value.
If you put a dot value
in it, then it will show
the error.
Here it is written that invalid
literal for integer with base 10,
3.4.
So 3.4 was a dot value,
decimal value.
So it was not allowed while
we are using integer before input
function.
So what else will you put
other than this?
When will the invalid value come?
When will it be written?
like if you put another number
like 11 then it will be
written as embedded value
otherwise you can see here if
it is integer then put integer
value
so it will restrict here if
you put a character
or if not put a decimal
value then it will restrict here
error will come that yes this
is integer and you put some
other data type value
so yeah that's it for today
class
so do like my video and
subscribe my channel and share this
video with your friends
comment down the any error or
any question you have I'll surely
reply and
that's it thank you